DEEPTHI SELVARA

D1, Ambience Aspen, Sarjapur Road, Bangalore, India - 560035, +919900543300 * deepthi.selvaraj@gmail.com

SENIOR EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT

A versatile and self motivated senior executive with Masters in Business Administration and 8+ years of progressive experience in Administration, Recruiting, Counselling, Marketing and Customer relation in an educational institute and Consulting firm. Expertized to operate effectively in a fast paced environment to meet tight deadlines with professionalism and exceptional communication skills. Well-versed with project management and time management skills such as prioritization, multitasking and delegation of duties.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Budgeting and strategic business planning
- Analysis and critical problem Solving with attention to detail
- Loyalty and Customer Acquisition
- Proactive and creative with Exceptional Business focused approach
- Microsoft Office skills

- Organizing and Hosting Events, Presentations and Meetings
- Hiring, recruiting and training knowledge
- Strong organizational skills, autonomy and team spirit.
- Marketing and Sales support.
- Matrix management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Parent Relations and Front office The Cambridge International School, Bengaluru, 04/2019 to Present.

- Associate with External agencies and bodies involved in the education sector to plan and execute the procedures and policies for affiliations.
- Report and provide seamless support to Directors/Principals by prioritization of business activities, travel and calendars.
- Monitor all administration functions including admissions, parent relations, project organizing meetings, events, and file management by exercising good judgment and keeping all the staff members informed.
- Collaborate with team members in Human resources, Academics and Finance department for induction, training and orientation sessions.
- Drive completion of key deliverables and follow up on outstanding issues pertaining to school programs.

Centre Head, Little Millennium Preschool, Bengaluru, May 2013 - April 2019.

- Plan, control and direct the overall operations of the school with 120 students and 16 faulty members.
- Staff recruitment, development and evaluation. Mentor teachers in the creation and implementation of powerful learning environments, lesson plans and necessary improvisation in their delivery in the classroom.
- School value promotion, program initiative, team building and shared decision making.
- Modify the general curriculum for the special needs based upon a variety of instructional techniques and activities.
- Organize Field trips, cultural programs, Sports day, annual day, State and National festivals and Music concerts for the students in the school programs conducted year on year.
- Preparation & Finalization of classroom layouts enhancing aesthetic appeal, creating learning corners, designing & placing equipment's and child friendly furniture & fixtures.
- Meet with officials and agencies involved in the education to discuss the plans on improving the curriculum for the purpose of helping the student to become more competitive for the primary schooling.
- Foster meaningful relationships amongst the parents, teachers and children through orientation programs and meetings to address the special needs of their children.

Associate Consultant, Career Net Consulting, Bengaluru, 11/2011 to 06/2012.

- Experienced in working for senior level requirements for IT services and Product based Companies and technology giants'/fortune clients in successfully closing the requirements.
- Worked closely for positions like- SSE's, Lead's, Technical Lead's, solution Architect's, Project and Program Managers.
- Worked in critical IT/ ERP hiring initiatives for potential clients (confidential) as a single point of contact (SPOC).
- Focused majorly on SAP, Oracle Apps and PeopleSoft, JDA Intactix requirements.

Compliance Officer, Alliance Care Ltd., Birmingham, 05/2010 to 08/2010

- Sourcing Screening Shortlisting. Pre-screened interviews of candidates looking for a job.
- Collecting database of clients and building business with the new clients. Organized and maintained the employee's filing system.
- Scheduled Interviews and interacting with clients. Trained employees on the areas that are required by the client.

Translator/Interpreter, Global Translational services, Birmingham, 02/2010 to 08/2011.

- Translated sentences of the health professional, police, solicitor and convey to people who are not fluent or the language being used is their second language.
- Coordinated Police interviews, court proceedings and solicitor interviews.
- Booked Medical appointments, social services appointments and community events.

Marketing Coordinator, Fixity Technologies, Chennai, 06/2007 to 07/2009.

- Administrative support for Corporate Sales Managers and the Director of Sales & Marketing.
- Communication with Executives to achieve reporting deadlines.
- Accurate production of key reports within deadlines for the Marketing Executives.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Education Volunteer, Bangalore, 05/2013 to 04/2019.

- Organized 25+ free medical camps, arts and crafts and sports activities for children and senior citizens in the
 preschool campus during the summer in coordination with other schools, hospitals, social and community centers,
 correctional facilities and detention centers.
- Participated with the children in the local community supported rallies in infrastructure development and save water/energy.
- Educated parents and teachers in choosing the appropriate education programs for their children.
- Volunteered in the marketing & advertising of The Cambridge International School during its promotional activities.
- As a skilled communicator able to build effective relationships with clients to provide companionship through genuine listening and conversation.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

MBA in International Business, Birmingham City University, United Kingdom, June 2012 **Bachelor of Engineering** in Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Anna University, April 2007 **International diploma** in early childhood care and education, August 2014

AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

- Awarded with Centre head showing excellence for academic years 2016 and 2017.
 Awarded with Franchisee excellence award for 2017 and 2018.